## PAVAN PREM KUMAR UPPADA

### **Data Engineer**

uppadapavanpremkumar@gmail.compavanpremkumar

**J** +52-8442772823

saltillo, Mexico

in pavanpremkumar-uppada

Career Objective: - 3+ years of IT experience in Business Intelligence Domain. Worked closely with business users and clients providing excellent SAP BO reports and PowerBI dashboards. Took leadership in managing Data ETL, Data Visualization and Maintaining the Data Warehouse. Aspiring to become Data Scientist and seeking to leverage my skills to improve company's and personal growth.

### **EDUCATION**

## M.Tech. in Data Analytics Birla Institute of Technology

**a** Aug 2020 - May 2022

Pilani, Raj, India

# B.Tech. in Computer Science GMR Institute of Technology

**i** Jul 2015 - May 2019

Rajam, AP, India

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Associate Trainee**

#### **Hexaware Technologies**

**i** Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

Chennai, India

Domain :- Business Intelligence & Analytics Roles & Responsibilities :-

- Worked with Data Scientist optimizing different ML algorithms. Increased accuracy of Logistic Regression and K-Means Clustering from 80 to 95%
- Worked on Python EDA's for different organizational level datasets
- Helped in managing, optimizing & deploying ML experiments using Azure ML Studio

## Data Engineer/Data Analyst Client:- Freeport-McMoRan

Sep 2019 - Ongoing

Saltillo, Mexico

Domain :- Manufacturing Consume Roles & Responsibilities :-

- Worked on migrating data from Azure Blob Storage to Snowflake using Azure Data Factory.
- Created automated python scripts running them in Azure Data bricks for sourcing real-time IOT data from SqlServer to Snowflake.
- Worked with Data Science team and build multiple PowerBI Dashboards from scratch including Data Modeling, Integrating with multiple data sources, DAX Querying and Deploying them in PowerBI Service.
- Interacted with Users to understand their business while gathering the Report requirements and provided several Report Mock-ups to finalize the requirements.
- Created SAP BO Reports with Customized SQL involving data from different tables and streams. And worked on enhancements of universes using Universe designer tool.
- Working on the SQL tuning and optimization of the SAP BO reports and PowerBI Dashboards.
- Part of support activities for the marketing strategies Webi reports, resolving Incidents, Change Requests and Service requests for Webi reports and universes within specified time limit.

### **SKILLS**

SQL Snowflake Microsoft PowerBI
SAP Business Objects Teradata ETL
Python Machine Learning Data Modeling
Azure(Data Factory,Databricks,Cosmos DB..)
NLP Data Analysis Agile Methodology

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Azure Data Engineer Associate Microsoft (06/2021 - 06/2023)
- Azure Data Analyst Associate Microsoft (03/2021 - 03/2023)
- Azure Data Scientist Associate Microsoft (03/2022 - 03/2023)

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**



#### **Project Related**

Completion of major project ahead of schedule, March 2022



**Target State Role - Top Performer** 

Completed Analytics Data science and IOT Engineer Exam

## **STRENGTHS**

Self-Learner Creative Team-Player
Adaptability

## INTERESTS

Learning New Technologies Playing Chess

Gym Travelling

## **LANGUAGES**

Telugu English Spanish

